A big part of my motivation for making this course came from a tweet, a post on X, that the
incredible Andrei Karpathy made a few months ago. And I put the tweet up here, Andrei Karpathy,
of course, he's one of the founding members of OpenAI. He's been across his work at
Tassa and OpenAI, and at Stanford. He is just such a luminary in the industry. And he's also the person that coined the term
"vibe coding," as we'll find out later.
And this was a tweet that he came up with late last year.
And I'm going to do the slightly unusual thing
of reading this tweet to you,
but adding some expression to it,
'cause I think it's so incredible.
Andres says, "I've never felt this much behind
"as a programmer.
"The profession is being dramatically refactored
"as the bits contributed by the programmer are increasingly
sparse and between. I have the sense that we could be 10x more powerful. If I could just properly
string together what's become available over about the last year and a failure to claim that
boost feels like a skill issue. There's this new layer of abstraction in addition to the usual layers that involves agents, sub-agents, their prompts,
context, memory, modes, permissions, tools, plugins, skills, hooks, mcp, lsp, slash commands,
workflows, id integrations, and the need to build an all-encompassing mental model
for strengths and pitfalls of fundamentally stochastic, fallible, unintelligible and changing entities" suddenly intermingled with what used to be good old-fashioned
engineering.
Wow, what a tweet.
And then Andre ends the tweet with "clearly, some powerful alien tool was handed around
except it comes with no manual and everyone has to figure out how to hold it and operate
it while the resulting magnitude 9 earthquake is rocking the profession.
Roll up your sleeves to not fall behind.
An inner nutshell, that, that tweet is what this course is all about.
This course, as I said at the beginning, it is the missing manual.
The idea is that at the end of this course you'll be able to bring back up this tweet
and read that through and you'll be able to say, "Yes, yes, yes. I know what
all these things mean. I know how they fit together. I know where they work well, where
they don't work. I can separate the hype from the facts." And I know how to navigate
this crazy new world of agentic AI coding. That is what I have in store for you over three
weeks. So who exactly is this intended for? Is it meant for people who are junior or for people who are senior coders, never coded
before?
You're an expert.
Well, here's the answer.
It's for two different types of people.
First of all, aspiring engineers, people who maybe are junior or not technical at all
today.
Maybe this is one of your first times ever writing code.
Or maybe you've written a bit bit but you consider yourself not yet an
expert. You will be able to build complete products, large-scale products
with confidence with the assistance of AI agents. And the other archetype, the
other person that I'm targeting this course for is actually people who are
senior staff engineers, people who are experienced coders, but either relatively
new to the Agentica AI coding, or you feel a bit like Andre's tweets, you feel like
there's just too much going on. How do you navigate all these different things? How
do you work them together to accelerate the most? And that's what this is about. I'm going
to allow you to accelerate what you can do to maximize the potential and importantly to keep
enjoying what you do.
Because a lot of what drives the passion for being an engineer for me and for
you is about solving problems and building great stuff.
And there's this sense out there that some of these AI tools are taking away
the enjoyment.
And I don't think that needs to be the case.
I think it changes the picture.
It means some things that I used to enjoy.
I don't do anymore, but there are new things that I things that I used to enjoy. I don't do anymore.
But there are new things that I enjoy that I can now do. And so it's a change in the equation.
It's a change in what we can do. And there's stuff to enjoy out of that as well.
And I know you know I'm going to say this, but of course I'm going to say that it's not
actually for those two archetypes of person. You have to be either an aspiring engineer or a
senior staff engineer, of course.
The idea is that there will be something
in this for everyone.
I'm going to talk to people that are relatively new
to coding or completely new, and to the experts too.
This is something that connects the dots.
And as a result, there'll be some things
that might be too advanced for you,
and that's okay.
Just get a gist of it and keep moving.
And for the experts, there's gonna be some stuff,
like how to set up cursor,
what's what's the project directory. There's going to be super obvious to you and don't worry just put me on
two x zoom through that. There's going to be tons of juicy stuff here. There's going to be something
for everyone across the spectrum of your technical experience. And so what will I leave you with
at the end of our three weeks together, you will be able to build and debug and troubleshoot and enhance existing software products at any scale,
whether it's a small, whether it's a first-person shooter game,
or whether it's a large team collaboration
with a massive repo or multiple repos,
whatever scale, whatever kind of problem you're working on,
you will be able to do it assisted by AI agents.
You will be able to take the greatest advantage
of the current landscape.
In other words, you'll be able to tweet back
at Carpathi and Andre and say, I get all this,
I know how to navigate it, I have the missing manual.
And thirdly and importantly, of course, increasingly,
if you look at job descriptions, people expect
that you have these kinds of skill sets.
So you're able to use a GenTic AI
to help you write code more efficiently.
And you'll be able to apply to those jobs
and show that you have the full skill set.
You know about MCP and skills and hooks and so on
and even Ralph Loops
and how to bring it all together
to deliver high quality software fast.
And by the way, I just wanna clarify something
that you'll hear me say a lot, which is that,
whilst I am an upbeat type, I'm generally an enthusiast, I am not caught up in the
Agentic AI hype. The tools that we're going to be using in the next few weeks are incredibly
powerful and allow us to do amazing things, but they are not without their downsides. There are
significant benefits and there are also drawbacks, and I'm going to make you very
aware of those drawbacks and being successful using agentic AI to write software is about
knowing about both the strengths and the weaknesses and being able to maximize the strengths and
being able to manage the weaknesses and that is what we will be doing.